<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>a[musing] - fiction</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/fiction.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2021-03-03T20:50:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>King Logan</title><link href="/king-logan.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-03-03T20:50:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-03-03T20:50:00-08:00</updated><author><name>kashilkarkunal</name></author><id>tag:None,2021-03-03:/king-logan.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The entire theatre was silent, the man on the stage commanding their unwavering attention, for this was the most important scene in the play.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The entire theatre was silent, the man on the stage commanding their unwavering attention, for this was the most important scene in the play. The scene was a maelstrom of emotions and the man was like a ship caught in that whirlpool, his every action governed by the emotion he had to portray next. The last scene of Act-2, it was the moment when the king discovered that his own brother had perpetrated an attack on the castle with the intention of deposing him and taking the throne for himself. The man, the king stood there nonplussed, looking at his brother, his eyes full of sorrow but his face rigid and jaw tight, seething with anger at the betrayal. He could not understand how this perfidy had gone unnoticed, how his brother had been able to kill his personal guards, how he, the greatest swordsman had been disarmed so easily!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brother’s eyes were full of hate and hunger, there was also triumph in those eyes. He did not meet his brother’s eyes but they were looking at the throne, the crown and a cynical smile spread across his face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Months of planning! Months of fawning to make sure you did not get a whiff of my plans. The culmination of my dreams, finally!’ he almost shouted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Why would you do this, Rogan? I trusted you, more than my ministers, more than Hawke!’ the King commanded, for even if he was cornered, even if it was his brother who stood before him, he was a King and a King commanded! He did not plead, he did not request, he only commanded, he listened to the advice from his ministers, his Chief-Commander but the final authority was his, and it was for everyone to obey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Why, you ask? But of course for the throne, the crown, the kingdom!’ said a cold voice. King Logan froze, his eyes snapped towards the source of the sound, so vehement, so vile he almost shuddered. Logan recognized the voice, there was no mistaking it, as it was the voice of the former Court Magician, Moran.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Moran! What is the meaning of this!?’ Logan thundered, his eyes red with fury! Rogan took a step back involuntarily, forgetting for a moment that he was the one who held the sword.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moran sneered and laughed viciously, ‘It is not just Rogan who could not bear the thought of you ruling this Kingdom, my Lord’, he added, mockingly. ‘We both have been planning for this moment, drawing up strategies, waiting for the right moment to strike and finally it has come!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Once Rogan has become the King, and a great King he would make’, he added with a bow to Rogan and continued, ‘the Kingdom would know of true glory! A King such as you, soft-hearted that you are, cannot achieve what is expected of this great Kingdom, and for this reason, you must be dethroned!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘You dare! You dare stand there and mock your King, Moran!? You dare call me soft-hearted!? I would never agree to sacrifice my people for your rituals, never!’ the King roared, ‘You talk of glory!? What kind of a King would sacrifice his people to capture more Kingdoms, what glory is there in filling the treasuries while the kingdom suffers!?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘And you Rogan, you are my brother! How have you fallen so low that Moran could sway your mind! It was for a reason I banished this man from my Kingdom! And you have brought him back and have taken his help so you could dethrone me? So you could kill me? How has this come to pass!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rogan, trembled, but regained his footing and replied, ‘Yes! Yes, I have! I could not sit next to you and watch the Kingdom waste away to a mere shadow of our father’s dream! It was then that I realized that it should be I who ruled this Kingdom! Me who fulfilled our father’s dream!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Rogan, have you no understanding of what father dreamt for this Kingdom!? Do you really believe that he dreamt for a Kingdom where the King cared not for his people, but led his armies to war? And for what!? So you could earn glory? You think that is what a great King should do!?’, Logan took a step towards his brother, his body trembling with anger and his eyes filled with rage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rogan stiffened and held up the sword, but he did not meet his brother’s eyes, could not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Do not listen to him my Lord! You will be the greatest King that has ever walked the Earth! All that is left is for you to kill this man, and the throne will be yours!’ Moran hissed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Do not listen to this snake, Rogan! He has poisoned your mind! You are a better man than that! I am certain of it! Help me destroy this evil man, together we can do it!’, the King shouted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rogan looked at his brother now, his eyes reflected the hesitation of his mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘I cannot brother! It is too late!’ Rogan said, shuddering at first then becoming more composed, ‘I must be the King for the sake of this Kingdom, for our father!’ Even as he said this he could not strike his brother, his mind racing back to the time when they were younger, learning to ride the horse, learning to fight and playing together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a sudden movement that Rogan only caught out of the corner of his eye. Moran had moved at an inhuman speed, his hand stretching farther than it should, his fingers now replaced by the head of a snake and the snake struck the Kings face! The King gave a cry of anguish and clutched his face with both his hands!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was almost the end of the play, Dan, playing the King had a small balloon filled with red paint that would be smeared across his face to reveal a King with disfigured face, only Dan would not stop screaming! He rolled on the floor and clutched his face in earnest. The crew members sensing something amiss gave the cue to pull the curtains. As the curtains drew across the stage, the crowd erupted in a thunderous applause drowning Dan’s screams, the rest of the actors rushed by his side to see what had happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As they moved his hands away, they saw Dan’s face, truly disfigured, the balloon had not contained red paint, it was acid and it burned Dan’s face and he screamed!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="fiction"></category></entry></feed>